export const chapter = "Chapter - 26: Media and Democracy ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the main role of the media in a democracy?",
        optionA: "Entertainment",
        optionB: "Disseminating information",
        optionC: "Conducting elections",
        correctAnswer: "B) Disseminating information",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is considered the fourth estate or organ of the government?",
        optionA: "Legislature",
        optionB: "Executive",
        optionC: "Media",
        correctAnswer: "C) Media",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What are the two main classes of media mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Television and radio",
        optionB: "Print media and electronic media",
        optionC: "Magazines and newspapers",
        correctAnswer: "B) Print media and electronic media",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who feeds the media with information, according to the text?",
        optionA: "Only government departments",
        optionB: "Only political parties",
        optionC:
          "Government departments, NGOs, political parties, industries, companies, etc.",
        correctAnswer:
          "C) Government departments, NGOs, political parties, industries, companies, etc.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary function of media ethics and accountability, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "To control the government",
        optionB: "To ensure biased reporting",
        optionC: "To prevent harm to people and the nation",
        correctAnswer: "C) To prevent harm to people and the nation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What form of media has become very powerful in recent times due to advancements in technology?",
        optionA: "Television",
        optionB: "Newspapers",
        optionC: "Social media",
        correctAnswer: "C) Social media",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the Right to Information Act, 2005, allow individuals to do?",
        optionA: "Control media content",
        optionB: "Seek information from government authorities",
        optionC: "Impose restrictions on the media",
        correctAnswer: "B) Seek information from government authorities",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary purpose of commercial advertisements mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Raise social awareness",
        optionB: "Sell products and services",
        optionC: "Provide solutions to problems",
        correctAnswer: "B) Sell products and services",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is a consequence of media not following ethics, as discussed in the text?",
        optionA: "Increased government control",
        optionB: "Public confusion due to biased reporting",
        optionC: "Strengthening democracy",
        correctAnswer: "B) Public confusion due to biased reporting",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How has the social media's unrestricted freedom been described in the text?",
        optionA: "A tool to spread rumors and biased information",
        optionB: "Government-controlled platform",
        optionC: "An efficient means of disseminating accurate information",
        correctAnswer: "A) A tool to spread rumors and biased information",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The period of emergency proclaimed in 1975-77 is known as the ________________ of democracy.",
        options: ["Golden Age", "Dark Period", "Revolutionary Phase"],
        correctAnswer: "Dark Period",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The media is often referred to as the ________________, along with the legislature, executive, and judiciary.",
        options: ["Fourth Power", "Fifth Estate", "Fourth Estate"],
        correctAnswer: "Fourth Estate",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Social media platforms like Facebook, WhatsApp, LinkedIn, and Twitter provide a platform for individuals to write and circulate information, making them part of the ________________.",
        options: ["Mass Communication", "Public Discourse", "Mass Media"],
        correctAnswer: "Mass Media",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Advertisers, who are the main source of revenue for newspapers and television channels, play a crucial role in the ________________.",
        options: ["Media Economy", "Media Power", "Media Industry"],
        correctAnswer: "Media",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Right to Information Act, 2005 allows individuals to seek information from any government authority, promoting transparency and curbing ________________.",
        options: ["Bureaucracy", "Corruption", "Secrecy"],
        correctAnswer: "Corruption",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The media helps form popular opinion by disseminating information and providing a forum for ________________ and debate.",
        options: ["Deliberation", "Consultation", "Discussion"],
        correctAnswer: "Discussion",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Commercial advertisements aim to sell products and services and can sometimes result in the promotion of ________________.",
        options: ["Consumerism", "Materialism", "Luxury"],
        correctAnswer: "Consumerism",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government officials can be made to work efficiently if ________________ is given, leading to the eradication of bribery.",
        options: ["Transparency", "Accountability", "Information"],
        correctAnswer: "Information",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The media is often criticized for not following ethical practices, leading to biased reporting and the spread of ________________ information.",
        options: ["True", "False", "Manipulated"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chief Information Commission of India, established under the Right to Information Act, is located in ________________.",
        options: ["Mumbai", "Delhi", "New Delhi"],
        correctAnswer: "New Delhi",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Democracy can thrive without the free flow of information.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The media's role in democracy is limited to disseminating information.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Social media platforms are not considered a part of mass media.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Advertisers have a minimal impact on the content and focus of media channels.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Right to Information Act, 2005 promotes transparency in government actions.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Commercial advertisements are solely meant to provide information to the public.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Social advertisements focus on raising awareness about social issues.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The government's role in providing information is limited to national security concerns.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Media ethics play a negligible role in responsible journalism.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chief Information Commission of India is located in Mumbai.",
        options: ["True", "False"],
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
